#### Contact

pallaviaggarwal123@gmail.co

www.linkedin.com/in/pallaviaggarwal-1003 (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

Python

Machine Learning

Natural Language Processing (NLP)

### Languages

Hindi

English

# Pallavi Aggarwal

Senior Analyst at HCL Technologies New Delhi

# Summary

Senior Analyst @DRYICE/HCL Technolgies. She has worked on the development and integration of various automation projects using natural language processing, machine learning and Python. She is experienced in the development of various cognitive chatbots using IBM Watson and Dialogflow. She has published a Book titled "Developing Cognitive Bots Using the IBM Watson Engines", Apress Publication, 2020. Strong engineering professional with a Masters of Engineering focused in Computer Science from Thapar University.

# Experience

HCL Technologies Senior Analyst June 2018 - Present (2 years 3 months) Noida Area, India

- \* Working in the DRYiCE division of HCL Technologies that is focused on building Al-powered products and platforms for the digital world.
- \* Working on iAutomate as a Back-end Developer, project that enables intelligent run-book automation through extensive use of proprietary natural language processing algorithms and knowledge analysis in tandem with an orchestration engine.
- \* Developed 'Recommendation System' Module in lautomate that suffice Runbook implemented using interactive Model, NLP concepts, TextRanking, JAVA.
- \* Worked on Python Project IKnowledge that converts unstructured large text data that is collected every day, into organized, Compact text form using NLP Concepts, Text Ranking, Clustering.
- \* Implemented and worked on chat-bots using Cognitive Engines such as IBM Watson And Dialog Flow.
- \* Worked on public cloud platforms such as IBM Cloud, GCP.
- \* She has quality development skills using latest technologies including Python, Solr HA, Mongo, Java, J2EE, WebAPI, Spring, SOAP, REST, Apache,

Tomcat, IBM Watson, Dialogflow, LUIS, GCP Auto ML and AI Platform service, SQL.

ST Microelectronics Internship Trainee June 2017 - May 2018 (1 year) Greater Noida

- \* As an Intern at STMicroelectronics Pvt. Ltd., I am a part of the T&DP (Technology and Design Platform) Department. The project is related to development of Business Administration Platform Management Tools such as Record Management, Schedule Database, and Budget Editor Etc. I led the effort to increase the performance of these Management Tools and responsible for research, planning and managing the project. Fixing the issues troubleshooting and new update from the client.
- \* Technology Used: Restful Web Services (Back end) in JAVA, Visual Basic Application (Front end), MySQL (Database), Glassfish server, Postman, Eclipse.

## CMC Academy Mohali Trainee July 2014 - December 2014 (6 months) Mohali

Developed a project with following key points

- \* Android based project Bug Tracker System.
- \* Bug Tracker is mobile application that keeps track the reported bug in software development project.
- \* Design and Develop coding project using Eclipse and SQLite Database.

## Education

Thapar University

Master of Engineering , Computer Science · (2016 - 2018)

Punjab Technical University

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Computer Science · (2011 - 2015)